<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description>Minimalist Jekyll theme for technical writing blog.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 22:10:17 +0530</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 22:10:17 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.0.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Summer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;February is almost gone. I remember two months ago I had an angst towards the strong winter. Now in hindsight I can see there were different reasons for my constant grumpiness and lack of motivation. Pushing right back was never been so hard. That time got lost in that space and now I understand about it better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;January ended with my second last semester, now the final semester has only one project and one course; and so I’ve been feeling quite free of all the tense work. As I’m writing this, I’m also wearing a T-shirt, which indicates that Summer is here. Feel like I’ve been missing it quite a lot. I’ve started learning a new game, and been giving most of my time to it. It’s wonderful. I’m also getting more frequent with my friends, and going out of house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There has been a lot of new events. Things I couldn’t possibly imagine happened. Despite of all the absurdists I quote, or pessimists I read, Life is beautiful and I do have the time. So will try to live the Summer as it’s meant to be.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 21:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2021/summer/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2021/summer/</guid>
        
        <category>summer</category>
        
        <category>twenty-twenty-one</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Indian English Poetry: A Course I Took This Semester</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I took a course on Indian English Poetry (HUL240) this semester. I had to talk about my experience in the last class, so I thought I’d post here too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had not read a lot of poetry, although I did start with Neruda, Pessoa, and maybe a bit Angelou. But after a “linguistic crisis” of some sort (after reading Witty boy), I wasn’t sure if I get the point of poetry. It was fascinating from an aesthetic point of view, but it seemed like an over-complicated way to explain or say something if used as a methodology of conveying ideas. I mean if you need to explain poetry for its ideas then it could’ve been written more clearly. So I wasn’t sure which part it plays in the language game. Although now it may seem that it might just have been a bad interpretation of Wittgenstein from my side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The point being: I haven’t read a lot of poetry; also haven’t read Indian-English writers. So I wasn’t familiar with the Indian symbolism and usage at all. In a way, I entered the course a bit blank and with a lot biased perceptions, obviously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I learnt that poetry play a role beyond self reflection and aestheticism. The moral conflicts and social constructs; personal issues, local problems and universal ideas; the post and pre-colonial politics; problems of caste that are unique to India are better socially reflected with poetry because they are conveyed better, and in a manner that creates familiarity to a range of readers. It “hits” the soul—if I may. Following something similar to Critical Theory and Frankfurt’s School of Thought: assessment and critique of society from the society in order to change structures. Also “Indianized English” as I’ve seen in the poetries, are unique in the form of imagery; something that I haven’t noticed yet in western literature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, it was a fun experience. I did miss a lot of classes though.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 21:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2021/indian-english-poetry-a-course-i-took-this-semester/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2021/indian-english-poetry-a-course-i-took-this-semester/</guid>
        
        <category>course</category>
        
        <category>poetry</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The End of a Cold Year</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This year—2020—has been a long and a cold year. Long: for the troubles it brought, for the days when something reckless wriggles in you, for the times when mind seems a bit tad distracted, for some things that are lost forever in the translation; and cold: for the situations it got me in, for the ideas that went through my head, and for some things that I find easier to forget than to say. One can look up in the sky and think that it will get over soon but it doesn’t, not so easily—no. It’s something like war, when war occurs people say that “it’s stupid, it’ll end soon,” but it doesn’t. It goes on, taking a major portion of lifetimes out of it. I think Camus said it. But as cold as it may seem, things do end; a bit different but they always do. I give the argument of finiteness for it. And I lay back with a smile on my face for that gives me an insane amount of happiness; just the finite bound of it. Oh what a thing to say!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it won’t end soon, probably will take another year or so. I’m ready for that, I got nothing against it. With the absurdity of life as it is, random things are bound to happen in any-and-all lifetimes, it’s nothing else if not normal in this sense. And I stand by it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the depths of winter, when the streets lay cold and soulless, everyone needs books to read and shows to watch. There were many books that resonated through me. The miserable of Dostov from The Brothers Karamazov, The Gambler, and The Double caught me but not by surprise; The artistic suffering of the ordinary mind that Gabo got me in by many works such as Love in the Time of Cholera, One Hundred Years of Solitude, Chronicles of a Death Foretold, Strange Pilgrims, No One Writes to the Colonel, Of Love and Other Demons, and some more—damn I read a lot of Gabo; There’s always some parts of Camus and Kafka that I discover which I hadn’t seen before—always something unseen, something unnoticed. There was a sweet introduction to the linguistic beauty of Nabokov and a daring simple usage by Peter Handke. Some surrealism of Murakami and an introduction to Russell. And some more. All-and-all they made my year good; for the year also brought a ton of sadness that I took from people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new year—though logically the same continuation—, mentally, will be a time to entertain new principles to live by. I hope the world become a better place as soon as possible. After the long winter, the summer is always beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope for a lot of things. I do not know why but I do. A lot goes on and I try to forget some. The last journal of the year 2020. It was alright.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 21:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020/the-end-of-a-cold-year/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020/the-end-of-a-cold-year/</guid>
        
        <category>winter</category>
        
        <category>summer</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>&quot;Bite Off More Than I Can Chew&quot;</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Listening to George R R Martin speak in a clean manner got me wondering how much complexity his books contain on an intentional level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find it personally delightful that a good king can easily be a bad ruler. The war is not always so clear; rarely it is between good or bad, it’s more complex than that. What tax policies the ruler will have? How will the ruler resolve a dispute of noble lands between old families? How will the ruler merge two complex religion that were fighting from an eternity? How much innovation and management goes into it? These are the questions that usually go unanswered. It’s rarely like Lord of the Rings where if darkness prevails all life will be in trouble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the times the wars doesn’t make any sense. For smallfolk and petty lords most wars neither gives them nor takes from them too much, but inevitably plays with their lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea of distorted perspective in a fiction is really intimidating. It raises the level of author’s intellect one step up from the reader. Martin said some of his POV characters might have told or heard incorrection information and that is bound to happen in a world where information travels either through letters or word of mouth. It’s funny how realistic it makes the fiction itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Westeros, Essos, Sothoroys and other remaining parts do follow up nicely in a fashion which any world evolved in itself should contain. There are waves of invasion to west-lands in successive periods of human evolution. Stronger is that religious faith which had showed their followers that their God is real. There are diseases, epidemics, destruction, and eventual consequence of blood magic. In a world so complicated there had to be thousands of characters involved as he has already created. It is inevitable if sound.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But as he puts it, “having thrown the balls in the air I feel compelled to keep on juggling them,” I do wonder that if he thinks he made a big mistake creating the world so complex. First three books, then six, then seven, and now it looks like nine to me. There are lots and lots of characters, plots, subplots, and all. I am fine with a bittersweet ending but it has to be complete that’s all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do have to wait a lot for it though.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 16:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020/bite-off-more-than-i-can-chew/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020/bite-off-more-than-i-can-chew/</guid>
        
        <category>george r r martin</category>
        
        <category>asoiaf</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Different Ironborn Are From First Men</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I feel like Ironborn are very different than First Men in multiple aspects. As the books suggest, First Men when explored Westeros starting from South to North, some of them discovered Iron Islands and lived there, which then later got called as Ironmen but a lot of things contradict with this assumption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, after the initial fights with Children of the Forest (CotF), First Men started believing in the Old Tree Gods. And since Iron Islands are too rocky for weirwoods to grow, no Tree Gods were present there; no roots no presence. Why would they just forget their Old Gods? Isn’t that a little against their belief system? How did the Drowned God suddenly came into picture? I don’t recall any instance of that in their legendary tale of The Grey King.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maesters believe the contradiction of the Seastone chair is just an exaggeration of the First Men but that doesn’t mean it can’t certainly be disregarded. The Maesters were among the Andals while the First Men didn’t have the ability to write and read, so it might as well be true. That a different species but close in evolution with First Men were already living on the Iron Islands before First Men came, and so the Seastone chair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also what about the difference in cultural aspect? Ironborn say they don’t sow. This goes totally against First Men who always sow. Sowing is part of their belief system about taking care of trees. Even the ideology of political system are different. The sons of the The Grey King decided to held a Kingsmoot; that’s basically a form of flawed democracy which is super different than the full Monarchial system for First Men, where bloodlines held the power to rule. Think about the way they name their castles. Pyke on Pyke, Harlaw, Orkmont. Why would they name their castles based on their names? Winterfell, White Harbour, Moat Caitlin; they aren’t named like that. Seems like culturally different way of naming castles and other things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These were just on top of my head but there are multiple different categories in which they can be differentiated. Iron Islands is such an interesting place for a historian.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 13:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020/how-different-ironborn-are-from-first-men/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020/how-different-ironborn-are-from-first-men/</guid>
        
        <category>asoiaf</category>
        
        <category>first men</category>
        
        <category>ironborn</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Madlad Who Wont Use the Letter F</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today the main page of Reddit is covered with the absolute madness of a reddit user: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/user/IHateTheLetterF&quot;&gt;u/IHateTheLetterF&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I came across it I thought it’s some kinda joke but since past 6 years he has not used the letter f, not even a single time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People at r/dataisbeautiful analysed his posts and comments: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/dataisbeautiful/comments/jyn8zo/oc_uihatetheletterf_is_a_mad_lad_extended_to/?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;amp;context=3&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/dataisbeautiful/comments/jyiwuq/oc_uihatetheletterf_is_a_mad_lad/?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;amp;context=3&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s pure madness from one end and as whimsical as it gets. His justification is: it almost looks like uncompleted E and can always be replaced with the sound of ‘ph’. Incomplete justification can always be given but that’s not the point. The point is the sheer will he maintained throughout the years. It’s so damn cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usually people cover their weird obsessions and incomplete opinions under the sweet cover of whimsical but I hardly see anyone being truly. This guy wins it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It almost certainly sounds like a cult I would join. I am definitely going to try this starting now. The letter which must not be typed.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2020 18:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020/the-madlad-who-wont-use-the-letter-f/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020/the-madlad-who-wont-use-the-letter-f/</guid>
        
        <category>madlad</category>
        
        <category>reddit</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Winds of November</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Half of November passed in an instant, rather unpleasant as of the relativity. Winter is here, which reminds me George R R Martin updated what’s going on in Westeros, and he gave me more hope for Winds and Winter release, it’s been almost 10 years (just to remind.) Pretty sure it’ll cross 1500 pages and that it will be divided into two books. And interpolating linearly the amount of plots and subplots he created, it might take him almost 3 more books to cover everything. I don’t think much about it though, the miserable kinda get me down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My Master’s Thesis project as I have chosen along side with (you know who) is super cool. Have to design a function-as-a-service microservice architecture over a dynamic pool of resources. Given that the semesters are too short, I’m not exactly sure how much we can do it, but we’ll try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GTA-V is too much detailed I noticed, as I’ve been playing it for long hours. I can’t even comprehend how complicated the code would have to be in order for the AI to automatically trigger a NPC’s gun as it hits the floor at the edge, damn that’s so cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also I didn’t know how much Cauchy did in mathematics but hey the guy is everywhere practically the last mathematician who knew everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh boy I sure procrastinate more than I think I do.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 23:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020/winds-of-november/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020/winds-of-november/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Individual Experience of Reality</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;From past few weeks I was comparing the standards of day to day reality between today and say a century ago. One of the most important thing is the experience of reality. Today there is no individual experience of reality, we are constantly linked with the social media in respect to information, pictures, media and the world along the same parameters. Now exchange of information is indeed required (for any better civilization) but as a consequence of “what to share” the experience of living has turned into a “collective” experience. Thus, in no way, the continuous assessments feels like a necessary thing exactly because the group identity takes over. “Being United” is good in subjects of peace and all but not how we experience things. Basically, what I like, and thus as a continuation, would like to go on and explore, is shielded by the idea of not being understood, which is completely ridiculous, but very obvious when I’m on my phone more than 5 hours a day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If need be edgy, it can be said that this case has arisen only because everyone has a smartphone and can use these simplistic application. The place is a wreck, full of stupidity.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 15:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020/individual-experience-of-reality/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020/individual-experience-of-reality/</guid>
        
        <category>journal</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Now It Is a Ghost Town</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently completed the COD4 MW and it was am-azing. The storytelling, intensity, guns, gameplay and music is by-far the best in COD series I’ve seen yet and I’ve not seen it all and so many more COD to go yay! I’ll continue with the next in series a couple of days later, after that I played Watch Dogs 2 but got bored with the concept in just a couple of missions, the whole idea of “hacking” stuff and then exploring the world seems too normative. And I can’t emphasize how much the simple idea of a “free-world” means.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In books I’ve finished the Brothers Karamazov. What a super dramatic world! In the beginning I was thinking what a long book but at the end I could have read two more equal parts of it, it’s so indulging. I hate that I love drama. Anyway, I started reading Murakami again, this time it is Norwegin Woods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Pandemic Boredom” is there, still, a lot of it. I stay in my holdfast, hours at a time, with nowhere to go. Somehow I’m sleeping a lot more and getting late with the menial essential tasks of life but the laziness persists.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 19:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020/now-it-is-a-ghost-town/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020/now-it-is-a-ghost-town/</guid>
        
        <category>journal</category>
        
        <category>pandemic</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Games, Books, and Dealing With the Lockdown</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The majority of the past week has been fun. I completed NFS Payback and Heat, both were good and enjoyable, though they went too hard on drag and drift races, a couple of them are fine, maybe in side contests, but covering 40% of the tasks with drifts doesn’t make much sense. There is the need for SPEED not GOOD TIRES.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also completed Call of Duty Black Ops I and II, which were the BEST because of all the amazing story-telling. Black Ops III is of 100GB so I’m first playing Modern Welfare and then will go back to III and IV parts. I also started playing Watch Dogs 2 and so far it’s alright and will start playing GTA-V in a couple of days. So there’s that. Games are taking all the fun. I should probably choose a POV shooting-based game to play online with, that sounds so much fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve read an ample amount of books this year but considering I have a lot of time on my hand, I will take up big ones that I usually don’t get started with. I picked up The Brothers Karamazov and so far the amount of drama they pushed me into is pretty surprising. Having read so much Gabriel Garcia Marquez, my extra-fondness for him can be seen with the fact that I started News of the Kidnapping out of the blue and continued to read for the first 50 pages without a blink. His style just catches me quick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides that I started taking enjoyment in small assignments of my Abstract Algebra and Multimedia Streaming whereas Indian English Poetry is so boring I can’t even comprehend. Though I like Poetry (obv) but reading Poetries from Colonial India around 1800 just doesn’t make much sense. Geez give me some verses on human emotions, I’m bad at those.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve also started going to a Park at night, which naturally gives me some dopamine that I need now more than over. Oh my first time using WSL2 on Windows, going alright till now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rest can’t say anything about lockdown, hopefully it ends soon and something good happens maybe Martin releases first manuscript of Winds of Winter, that’d be so lovely though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alright, another journal, will write more. Farewell.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 23:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020/games,-books,-and-dealing-with-the-lockdown/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020/games,-books,-and-dealing-with-the-lockdown/</guid>
        
        <category>lockdown</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
